I kind of don't like the fact that the day is over just as the sun is rising.
(おりょう)なんか や～ね｡
朝日が昇るとともに➡
１日の終わりを
迎えるっていうのも…｡
That's the life of a hostess, but it's not healthy.
(おりょう)お水の宿命だけど
不健康 極まりないわ｡
(お妙)そう？
なかなか ｵﾂなものじゃない｡
Really? I think it's pretty good.
While's the sun's down we become the suns that light up the night.
太陽が沈んでいる間は
私たちが 夜を照らす太陽なのよ｡
Besides, a Bäagen-Dash after work tastes so good.
それにね 仕事終わりに食べる
ﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭは 格別だわ｡
(おりょう)お妙 ｱﾝﾀはいいわね｡
ﾉｰﾃﾝｷで…｡
Otae, you're lucky you're so relaxed. I can't take it anymore.
(おりょう)私 もう や～よ！
今日も 坂本とかいう浪人に➡
Today some ronin named Sakamoto was touching my butt.
ｹﾂ ﾍﾞﾀﾍﾞﾀ触られて…！
Honestly. Get used to it, Oroyo-chan.
(お妙)もう 慣れなさいよ
おりょうちゃん｡ そんなときは➡
I told you to break their fingers when they do that.
指を こう 逆に
ﾎﾞｷｯてしなさい って言ったでしょ｡
Is that what you do?!
(おりょう)ｱﾝﾀ
そんなこと やってんの!?
You're no sun! You're a black hole!!
(おりょう)どこが太陽？
ﾌﾞﾗｯｸﾎｰﾙよ！
新しく入った花子も
ｱﾝﾀくらい たくましかったらねぇ｡
If only Hanako, the new girl, was as tough as you.
今日も お休みしてたわね｡
どうしたのかしら？
She took off from work today, too, didn't she? I wonder what's wrong.
Who knows? It's not all that unusual. It's hard work.
さ～ね｡
この世界じゃ 珍しくないわよ｡
厳しい世界だから…｡ あれ？
Huh?
(おりょう)あれ 花子じゃない？
なに やってんのかしら？
Isn't that Hanako? I wonder what she's doing there...
(おりょう)あんなところで…｡
Hey!!
ちょっ…！
なに やってんの!? ｱﾝﾀ！
What are you doing?
(花子)こっち 来んといて！
D-Don't come any closer!
Hanako-chan...
(お妙)花子ちゃん…｡
(おりょう)ｱﾝﾀ こんな…！
You...
I was wondering what you were doing when you took off from work...
(お妙)仕事 休んで
何を やってるかと思えば➡
こんな…｡
If you want to catch crayfish, you should try a shallower river!!
ｻﾞﾘｶﾞﾆなら
もっと 浅い川で獲りなさい！
違うわ!!
状況をよく見ろ 状況を!!
She's not looking for crayfish!
I can't take it anymore. I've had enough. Goodbye!!
ｳﾁ もう 何もかも
ｲﾔになってしもうてん！
もう ええねん！ さいなら!!
Look out!!
危ない!!
ぎぇぇ～っ!!
ﾌｩ～ 危なかった…｡
That was dangerous.
ｱﾝﾀが いちばん危ないわ！
You're more dangerous!!
[Your dream will be granted if you believe... What is your dream?]
[My dream is for the Gin Tama anime to not end and continue past April.]
["People with Dark Pasts Can't Shut Up"]
[Kodokan Dojo]
Sis sure is late.
(新八)遅いなぁ 姉上｡
今日は せっかく お金 入ったから
鍋 作ったのに…｡
I got paid today, so I made nabe.
She's probably slinging it to a customer after hours. It's ready to eat, by the way.
(銀時)客と ｱﾌﾀｰでも
決め込んでんじゃねえの？
こっちのほうは できたぜ｡
ちょっと…
なに入れたんすか？ これ｡
Hey, what did you put in there? It looks like a witch's brew.
魔女が ｸﾞﾙｸﾞﾙかき回してる➡
謎の液体みたいに
なってるじゃないすか｡
Anyway, I put in everything from the fridge.
とりあえず 冷蔵庫にあるもの
ひととおり入れたなぁ｡
鍋は いろいろ入れたほうが
うまいからなぁ｡
Nabe taste best when you put in all sorts of things. What do you think, Kagura?
どうだ？ 神楽｡
(神楽)銀ちゃんの
足の裏みたいな味するよ｡
It tastes like the bottom of your foot.
Hey, that's terrible. My feet are weapons.
おいおい 最悪じゃねえか｡
兵器だよ それ｡
They're your feet. What are you going to do?
自分の足の裏でしょうが｡
どうすんですか もう…｡
I could try taking more showers.
清潔にするよう 心がけるよ｡
I'm not talking about your feet. I'm talking about the Nabe! Nabe!!
ｵﾒｴの足じゃねえよ！ 鍋だよ 鍋!!
(お妙)ただいま～｡
I'm home.
やばい… 帰ってきた｡
Oh no.
She's back. Sis is back. She's back. She's back. She's back.
Do we have any ingredients left that can save this thing?!
この状況を打破できる具材は
残ってねえのか？
そうだ！ ｵﾚの足を入れてみるか｡
That's it!! I'll put my feet in. The same nasty flavors might cancel each other out.
同じにおいが ぶつかり合えば➡
相殺されるかもしれん！
(鼻歌)
神楽ちゃん！
ちょっとそれ なに入れてんの!?
Kagura-chan, what are you putting in there?
ﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭ ｱｲｽｸﾘｰﾑだよ｡
It's Bäagen-Dash ice cream.
ｱﾈｺﾞ ﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭ 大好きだ って
言ってたから➡
Sis said she loves Bäagen-Dash, so she's bound to love this.
きっと 喜んでくれるね｡
Kagura-chan, that's like tossing her favorite things down the drain.
神楽ちゃん… それはね➡
好きなものを
ﾄﾞﾌﾞに捨ててるようなものだよ｡
片づけよう｡
こんなの ないほうがいい！
Let's clean up.
It's better if we get rid of this!! Destroy all the evidence!
ないほうがいいよ～!!
やめろや！ あきらめるな!!
Stop that. Don't give up. The match is over if we give up!!
あきらめたら そこで試合終了ね！
(お妙)新ちゃ～ん！
Shin-chan, do you know where the Bäagen-Dash is? I put it in the fridge.
The match has been cancelled due to excessive nabe.
(お妙)冷蔵庫に入れてた
ﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭ 知らない？
うっ！
やべえ！
This is bad. She's already noticed the Bäagen-Dash missing.
ﾔﾂめ ﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭに
早くも気づきやがった！
Dig it out! Where's the ladle?!
おたまは どこ いった！
ﾑﾘﾑﾘ！ もう溶けてますよ～！
Hot hot hot hot...
Forget it! It's already melted.
Hot!!
ｱｯﾁ～!!
Welcome.
[Oedo Mart]
(店員)いらっしゃいませ～｡
One hundred cartons of Bäagen-Dash please.
(２人)ﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭ 100個ください｡
Sir, even if you get a hundred cartons of Bäagen-Dash, your wish won't be granted.
(店員)お客さ～ん 言っとくけど➡
ﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭは 100個 集めても
別に 願いとか叶わないよ｡
いいから 100個 持ってこいって
言ってんだろ！ ﾊｹﾞ！
Just bring me a hundred cartons, baldy.
(お妙)ごめんなさいね｡
Sorry.
ﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭで 花子ちゃんにも➡
I was thinking of cheering you up with some Bäagen-Dash...
元気 出してもらおうと
思ったんだけど…｡
I tried to stop them. They're really hopeless.
私 さんざん止めたね｡
まったく しようがないﾔﾂらｱﾙ｡
Well, at least we have nabe. Hanako-chan, have some.
まぁ 鍋も いいんじゃない？
花子ちゃんも 食べてくださいな｡
Oh. You don't like nabe?
あら お鍋は嫌い？
花子ちゃんは
たしか 大阪出身よね？
You were from Osaka, weren't you? Would you like an okonomiyaki instead?
[NOTE: Okonomiyaki is a Japanese dish which consists of a variety of toppings that are placed onto or mixed into a batter which is fried. Toppings vary from region to region. Osaka is known for its okonomiyaki.]
お好み焼きとかのほうが
よかったかしら？
Okasa? Are you a migrant worker? Me too. We're alike.
ｵｰｶｻ？ 出稼ぎｱﾙか？
私もｱﾙ｡ 仲間ね｡
Hanako-chan...
(お妙)花子ちゃん？
あかん ごめん…｡
Oh no, sorry.
江戸に来てから
人の優しさに触れたことなんて➡
Ever since I came to Edo, I haven't experienced much kindness.
あんま なかったもんやから…｡
ｱﾝﾀみたいな人 おったんやなぁ
こんな近くに…｡
I never thought that people like you lived here.
花子ちゃん…｡
ｵｰｶｻ どうした!?
Hanako-chan...
Okasa, what's wrong? Cheer up!
[NOTE: Kagura calls her "Okasa" instead of "Osaka". It is a slang term.]
元気 出せよ ｵﾒｴ！
飲め これ飲め！
Have a drink!! Drinking makes everything better!
負けんな！ 都会に負けんな～!!
(お妙)花子ちゃん よかったら
話を聞かせてくれない？
Hanako-chan, do you think you can talk about it?
私にも できることがあれば
力になるし…｡
I'd like to help. After all, we're coworkers and friends...
私たち
同じ店で働く 仲間じゃないの｡
お妙ちゃん…｡
Otae-chan...
Really? Will you really help me?
(花子)ﾎﾝﾏに？ お妙ちゃん
ﾎﾝﾏに 力になってくれるん？
(お妙)えぇ 私でよければ｡
Yes. If you'd like.
あのぅ…
それなら 言いづらいけど おか…｡
Umm... In that case... This is difficult to say, but...m...
I won't lend you any money.
金は 貸さねえぞ｡
(花子)ﾊ… ﾊﾊﾊﾊ まさか…｡
O-Of course not...
話… 聞いてくれる？
Will you listen to my story?
(神楽)はぁ～？
ﾄﾞﾘｰﾑｷｬｯﾁｬｰ？
Dream catcher?
Yes. I fell for something pretty terribly...
そやねん｡ えらいもんに
引っ掛かってしもうて…｡
私は 江戸へは 踊り子になる夢
つかむために来たんやけど➡
I came to Edo to fulfill my dream of becoming a dancer,
(花子)そのために貯めた資金も
全部 巻き上げられてしもうた｡
but I was swindled out of all the money I'd saved up.
Why?
どうして そんな…｡
(花子)騙されてん！
I was tricked! They took advantage of my weakness.
ｱｲﾂら 人の弱みに つけこんで…！
((営業：へぇ～！
ﾀﾞﾝｻｰになりたいんだ｡
[Low Flower Cafe]
Oh? You want to become a dancer.
So that's why you're saving up your earnings at a snack house.
(営業)そのために
ｽﾅｯｸで 資金を貯めているわけか｡
That's very admirable. I never knew there were young people with such ideals!
立派だね～ 今どき
そんな若者がいたんだねぇ｡
(営業)でもね 残念なことに
志だけでは 夢はつかめないの｡
But you can't achieve your dream just by hoping for it.
If you could, the world would be filled with pilots and baseball players.
そんなもので
夢が つかめるくらいなら➡
世の中 ﾊﾟｲﾛｯﾄと野球選手だらけに
なってしまうわ｡
志は 夢を追う力｡
夢を得るには➡
Hope is the power to pursue your dreams.
But you need another power in order to achieve them.
これに もう１つ
夢をつかむ力がいるわけさ｡
We call it a dream catcher. Have you heard of it?
我々は これを ﾄﾞﾘｰﾑｷｬｯﾁｬｰ と
呼んでいるけど 知ってる？
ﾄﾞﾘｰﾑｷｬｯﾁｬｰ？
Dream catcher?
That's right.
そう！ しかし この力は➡
Most people would say that you either have the power to catch dreams or you don't.
残念ながら
後天的に身につくものではなく➡
生まれながらに もつ人
もたざる人がいるわけ｡
Some people are born with it and others are born without.
我々 夢幻教は
その生まれもってのﾊﾝﾃﾞｨｷｬｯﾌﾟを➡
The Dream Faith shows us how to overcome our innate handicaps in order to make everyone and ourselves happy.
克服する術を みんなに伝授して➡
みんなで幸せになっちゃおうって
そういう教えなんだ｡
ｷﾐは 知ってる？ 世の中で➡
Do you know the one thing held in common by everyone who has achieved their dreams?
夢をつかんだ成功者たちが
もってる １つの共通点を…｡
Prince Leyasu, Hideyoshi Toyotomi, the soccer player Pide
[Note: Pide = Hide Tanaka, Chinjo = Tsuyoshi Shinjo]
(営業)かの 家康公も
豊臣 秀吉も➡
ｻｯｶｰのﾋﾟﾃﾞも 野球のﾁﾝｼﾞｮｰも➡
and the baseball player Chinjo were all born with this.
みんな生まれながら
これを もっていたわけ｡
そして 我々は 人工的に これを
作り出すことに成功したわけ｡
We've succeeded in producing it artificially.
And here it is!
それが… これさ!!))
What is that?
(お妙)な～に？ それは…｡
(花子)なんか 夢 叶えた人は➡
They said that people who achieved their dreams had a mole sprouting hair somewhere on their body.
体の どっかに 毛が生えたﾎｸﾛが
あった っていうてな➡
高い金 出して つけﾎﾞｸﾛ買うてん｡
I spent big money for this stick-on mole. But nothing happened. I was duped.
やのに な～んも起こらへん｡
ﾎﾝﾏ 騙されたわ！
(花子)うわぁ～っ!!
おのれは ﾊﾞｶか～!!
Are you stupid?! Are you going to let that tiny bean dictate your life?!
そんな ちっさい黒豆で
人生 左右されてたまるか！
Were you planning on dancing with that dirty-looking mole?! A mole with a hair on it?!
(お妙)そんな汚らしいﾎｸﾛ携えて
ﾀﾞﾝｽ踊るつもりだったんか!?
這い上がってこい！
泥の中から這い上がってこい!!
Okasa!! This is no time to hide your head in the stew!
(花子)はぁ はぁ はぁ…｡
What else happened to you?
(お妙)それで？
他には どんな被害に遭ったの？
There, there. You did great, Okasa. Next time, let's try for thirty-seconds.
よ～し よし｡ よくやった ｵｰｶｻ｡
次は 30秒いってみよう！
(花子)それから
夢幻教に入信させられて➡
I then converted to the Dream Faith.
あと…
新聞の勧誘とか断りきれんで➡
Oh... Also, I couldn't refuse newspaper solicitations, so I ended up subscribing to nine papers...
９紙くらい とっちゃったり
消火器20本くらい買わされたり…｡
もう 江戸は怖いわぁ！
Edo is so overwhelming!! I can't live in this concrete jungle.
私 こんなｺﾝｸﾘｰﾄｼﾞｬﾝｸﾞﾙで
生きていけへん！
ｵﾒｴは ﾅﾏｹﾓﾉしかいない
ｼﾞｬﾝｸﾞﾙでも 生きてけねえよ｡
You wouldn't even be able to live in a jungle filled with sloths.
大阪は 人情の街や｡
Osaka was a warm-hearted town.
Naturally, there were bad-tempered people,
もちろん たちの悪いのも
おるけど➡
みんな どこか
他人とは思えへん➡
but everyone had a certain kind of warmth that you'd never expect from a stranger.
あったかいもんをもっとる…｡
But everyone in Edo is so cold.
けど… 江戸はみんな冷たいねん｡
People treat each other like strangers. I don't have the confidence to live here.
他人は他人って 一線 引いとる｡
ｳﾁ… もう ここで
やってく自信ないわ！
死ぬほど苦しいなら➡
If you're suffering that badly, then shouldn't you go back home?
地元に帰ったほうが
いいんじゃない？
You can dance anywhere.
踊りなんて どこでだって
踊れるんだから…｡
(お妙)ﾊﾅから 人に頼り切って
生きている人は➡
But wherever you go, I think you should learn to take care of yourself a little better.
どこいったって
うまくやっていけるとは➡
思えないけど… でも➡
But...
まだ江戸に残って
夢を追うっていうなら➡
If you still want to pursue your dream in Edo, I'll help you out.
私は いつでも力を貸すわよ｡
江戸には 江戸の
人情ってものがあるんだから｡
Edo has its own brand of warmheartedness.
ねぇ？ 銀さん…｡
あぁ？
Right... Gin-san?
♪♪～
[Dream]
Fellow believers! Do you have dreams?!
(斗夢)みなさぁ～ん！
夢 見てますか!!
(信者たち)見まくってま～す！
We dream like crazy!!
(斗夢)夢に向かって
走り続けてますか～！
Are you running after your dreams?
(信者たち)走りまくってま～す！
We run like crazy!!
はい 皆さん 今日も
夢いっぱい 元気いっぱいで➡
Well, everyone, what a joy it is to see you all so full of the faith!
私も嬉しいです！
その調子で 夢 追いかければ➡
If you continue chasing your dreams at this pace, you'll catch those dreams any day now!!
明日あたり
つかめるんじゃないかなぁ？
うん… えぇっと今日はね➡
Umm, today, Hanako, who dreams of being a dancer, has brought us some new dream chasers.
ﾀﾞﾝｻｰ志望の花子ちゃんが➡
新しい夢追い人を
連れてきてくれました｡
(斗夢)皆さんに 紹介します｡
Let me introduce them to you all.
はい 皆さん！ 夢 見てますか？
Hello, everyone! Do you have dreams?!
(みんな)見まくってま～す！
We dream like crazy!!
志村 妙さん…
あなたの夢は 何ですか？
Tae Shimura-san, what is your dream?
父の道場を復興させることです｡
To rebuild my father's dojo.
花子ちゃん… ｷﾐの夢は
言わずと知れた…｡
Hanako-chan, do you know what your dream is?
巻き上げられたお金を
取り戻す…｡
To get my money back from a phony relig-
私の夢は ご飯１膳に
海苔の佃煮 １ﾋﾞﾝ➡
My dream is to eat a bowl of rice covered with a whole jar of seaweed tsukudani.
[NOTE: Tsukudani is seafood or meat that has been boiled in soy sauce]
まるまるかけて 食べることです！
But if it comes true, I won't have anything to dream about, so forget it!!
でも 夢は叶うとさびしいから➡
ずっと胸に
しまっておこうと思います！
Is that so?
(斗夢)はい そうですか…｡
You probably want better eyesight. I don't need to ask you.
(斗夢)ｷﾐは…
目がよくなりたいとか➡
そんなんだろ どうせ… いいや｡
おぉい！ ちゃんと聞けやぁあ!!
Hey. Ask me!!
んっ？ ｷﾐの夢は…｡
What's your dream?
夢… そんなもの 遠い昔に
落っことしてきちまったぜ…｡
Dreams? I threw that kiddie crap away a long time ago.
(斗夢)お前 何しにきたんだぁ!?
Then why did you come here?
Look, I'm not gonna fake it, okay?
んなこと言われても
ねえもんは ねえんだって！
なんか ｻﾗｻﾗﾍｱｰになりたいとか
そんなんでいいんじゃないすか？
How about silky hair or something?
じゃ ｻﾗｻﾗﾍｱｰで｡
(斗夢)帰れぇえ～！
Sure, I'll go with that.
Get out of here!!
ｷﾐたち ﾛｸな夢をもたずに
ここへ入信してくるとは➡
Those are the lamest dreams I've ever heard of! What are you after?
どういうつもりだ？
ﾎﾝﾄに信者か!?
Are you really believers?
ｿｲﾂぁ… これから決める｡
Maybe I still need to be convinced. I hear you've got the power to grant dreams.
なんでも ｱﾝﾀ…
夢 叶える神通力が➡
使えるらしいじゃねえか｡
I wanted to see it with my eyes.
ｿｲﾂを この目で
一度 拝んでみたくてなぁ…｡
銀さん！ ちょっと
目的 忘れてるんじゃないすか？
Gin-san!! Aren't you forgetting why we're here?
まぁ 待てよ…
金 取り返す前に➡
Wait. Before we get her money back, shouldn't we reveal what he truly is?
ｺｲﾂの化けの皮 はがすのも
一興だろ？
Who are you?
(信者)なんだぁ お前ら！
(信者)斗夢様を愚弄するﾔﾂは
許さんぞぉ！
We won't let you make fun of Tomu-sama!!
(信者たち)消えろ 消えろ…｡
Get out! Get out!
(斗夢)ﾌｯﾌｯﾌ… おもしろい
私の力が見たいと？
How amusing... You want to see my power?
ここは 夢を叶えることのできる
理想郷…｡
This is a utopia where dreams come true.
ここで修練を積めば
ｷﾐたちも 私のように➡
If you train here, I'll teach you... How to gain the power to grant dreams like I can.
夢を叶える力を
得ることができることを➡
教えてやろう…｡
Dream Catcher!!
ﾄﾞﾘｰﾑ…！
ｷｬｯ… ﾁｬｰ！
なにやってんの…？
What are you doing?
ｷﾐ… ものっそい
ｻﾗｻﾗﾍｱｰになりたいって➡
You said your dream is to have silky hair, right? Take a look at your head.
言ってたよね？ 頭をご覧よ｡
I-Impossible. Gin-san's naturally wavy hair has...
ﾊﾞｯ… ﾊﾞｶな!? 銀さんの 天ﾊﾟが！
(お妙)ｻﾗｯｻﾗﾍｱｰに!?
Become silky!!
♪♪～
っていうか
髪型 変わってんじゃねえか～！
Your hairstyle has even changed, too!
ｳｿ!? ｳｿだと言ってよ！ ちょっ…｡
Really? You're joking, right? Hey.
Wow!
おぉ～！ ｻﾗｯｻﾗじゃねえか!!
It's all silky!!
ﾍﾞﾀつかない ﾊﾟｻつかない
じゃねえかぁ～！
It doesn't stick together or fly away!
ﾔｯﾎ～ｲ！ これで雨の日も➡
Yahoo!! Now it won't get tangled on rainy days!!
ｸﾘﾝｸﾘﾝにならなくてすむぜ！
Before you start celebrating, grieve over that hair style!!
喜ぶ前に ﾍｱｰｽﾀｲﾙを嘆け！
ｱｯﾊｯﾊ！ 見たかい
これがﾄﾞﾘｰﾑ ｷｬｯﾁｬｰだ!!
Now do you see? This is the Dream Catcher!!
夢幻教を信じる者は
この力が手に入るんだよ｡
Those who believe in the Dream Faith can gain this power.
みんな 夢が叶うんだよ！
The power to grant everyone's dreams.
What's the meaning of this?
いったい どういうこと？
これは…｡
何か 絶対 ﾀﾈがあるはず…｡
ねぇ 銀さん！
There must be some sort of trick to it.
Right, Gin-san?
何かご用があれば
なんなりとお申し付けください｡
I am yours to command, Ham-sama.
ﾊﾑ様｡
(斗夢)いや ﾊﾑじゃないから｡
It's not Ham, it's Tomu.
斗夢だから｡
おいぃい！
Hey!
I don't like this kind of Gin-san. Get a grip, Gin-chan.
あんな銀ちゃん 私 ｲﾔよ！
しっかりしてよ 銀ちゃん！
You...
お前！ 元の銀ちゃんを返すね！
Give us back the old Gin-chan.
What are you talking about? This is my true self.
なに言ってんだ…
これが本当の姿だよ｡
悪い坊主の呪いで
醜い天ﾊﾟに変えられていたのさ｡
An evil priest put a curse on me that made my hair ugly and naturally wavy.
そんなこと言うな！
自分に自信をもてぇ!!
Don't say that! Have confidence in yourself.
お前から 天然ﾊﾟｰﾏをとったら
何が残るんだ!?
What are you without your naturally wavy hair?!
ﾌﾌﾌ… お嬢さん｡
Young lady, your dream was to have a bowl of rice with a mountain of seaweed tsukudani on it, wasn't it?
ｷﾐの夢は ご飯１膳
まるまる海苔の佃煮だったね？
(斗夢)ｵｰｹｰ ｵｰｹｰ…｡
Okay, okay.
ﾄﾞﾘｰﾑ…！
Dream Catcher!!
ｷｬｯ… ﾁﾔ～!!
うぉっ！ ﾏｼﾞ出たぁ!!
Whoa!! It really appeared!!
何かご用があれば
なんなりとお申し付けください｡
I am yours to command, Ham Man.
ﾊﾑの人｡
(斗夢)なに？ ﾊﾑの人って｡
What do you mean "ham man"? I told you, I'm Tomu.
斗夢って言ってんじゃん！
やられた…｡
He got her too! And so easily!!
簡単にやられたぁ…｡
皆さ～ん 歓迎しましょう！
Everyone, let's celebrate. We have new members!!
ここにまた 我々の
新しい仲間ができました！
みんなで夢をつかんで
幸せになりましょう！
Let's achieve our dreams and be happy!!
Praise the Dream Faith!!
(信者たち)夢幻教 ﾊﾞﾝｻﾞｰｲ！
夢幻教 ﾊﾞﾝｻﾞｰｲ！
Praise the Dream Faith!!
Dureammmm...
(銀時/神楽)ﾄﾞﾘｰﾑ…➡
ｷｬｯﾁｬｰ！
Catcha!!
Not like that!!
(先輩)だから 違うって！
You focus too much on the pronunciation. You're not putting any feeling into it.
ｷﾐたちさぁ
発音に こだわってばっかで➡
全然 気持が
入ってないんだよね～｡
Feeling? All right. I think I can do it now.
気持すか…
先輩！ わかりました!!
なんか 今なら
やれそうな気がします！
Die, ugly!!
(神楽)死ねぇえ！ ﾌﾞｻｲｸ!!
(先輩)ちょっ… 気持って
それ 殺意じゃん！
Hey, those feelings are of murderous intent! What are you doing?
They've forgotten why we're here and have completely fallen into their trap.
目的 忘れて すっかり
ﾊﾏっちゃってますけど…｡
These are my feelings towards you. Please accept them.
ﾊﾞｶは 放っておきましょ｡
Leave those idiots.
Keep them to yourself!
でも これだけの信者がいるのも
わかった気がしますよ｡
Anyway, I'm beginning to understand why he has so many followers.
あんなもの
目の前で 見せられたら…｡
They were shown that... I wonder how he did it.
いったい どうやったんですかね
あれ…｡
Shin-chan, we didn't come here to prove that he's a fraud or anything.
新ちゃん… 私たちは➡
別に ｲﾝﾁｷを暴きにきた
わけじゃないでしょ？
If you forget what we came here to do,
目的を忘れて
余計なことに気をとられると➡
you'll end up like those idiots.
あのﾊﾞｶたちのようになるわよ｡
You're right.
そうですね…｡
We've got to get Hanako-san's money back from that phony religious leader and put Hanako-san at ease.
早く あのｲﾝﾁｷ教祖から
金を取り返して➡
花子さんを
安心させてあげなきゃね｡
No.
違うわよ…
ｲﾝﾁｷ教祖から 金を巻き上げて➡
We're here so we can extort money from that phony religious leader and rebuild our father's dojo.
父上の道場を復興させるのが
私たちの目的でしょ？
なにそれ？
知らないよ そんな目標！
What? I I don't remember agreeing to that objective!!
いつ掲げたの!?
だまされた善良な市民のお金➡
When did that become the plan?!
Are you planning on taking money that was tricked out of the hands
of good people for your own selfish purposes?
私欲に使うつもりですか！
There's nothing wrong with receiving a little reward money.
(お妙)礼金として
少々いただいても➡
ﾊﾞﾁは 当たらないでしょ…｡
残ったお金は➡
We're going to save the rest of the money.
ちゃんと貯金するわ｡
全部いただいてるじゃないすか！
You're taking all of it!!
ｱﾝﾀ ﾊﾅからそのつもりで来たな！
You planned on doing that from the start.
見損なわないでちょうだい｡
Don't make me sound like a crook. I plan on getting back Hanako-chan's money.
花子ちゃんのお金は
ちゃんと返すつもりよ｡
あら… そういえば
花子ちゃんはどこに…｡
Oh, come to think of it, where's Hanako-chan?
ﾄﾞﾘｰﾑ… ｷｬｯﾁｬｰ！
Dream Catcher!
Honestly...
(お妙)まったく…｡
How any times do you have to be duped for you to learn?
(お妙)あなたは
何度 だまされたら 学習するの！
Come on, take us to Jam's room.
さぁ ｼﾞｬﾑの部屋まで
案内してちょうだい！
Sis, it's Tomu.
姉上 斗夢です｡
(花子)違うで ﾃｨﾑや…｡
No, it's Tim... Huh? I'm not sure anymore...
(花子)あれ？
わからんようになってもうた…｡
(花子)どないするつもりやねん？
お妙ちゃん｡
What do you plan to do, Otae-chan?
(お妙)ここは
長居する場所じゃないわ｡
We shouldn't stay here long. Let's go after the safe in Timroth's room.
直接 ﾃｨﾑ･ﾛｽの部屋の金庫を
狙いましょ｡
Who's Timroth? That doesn't even resemble his name anymore!
ﾃｨﾑ･ﾛｽって 誰!? もう
原形なくなってんじゃないすか！
金庫 襲うって まるで泥棒やん｡
のらへんわぁ｡
Cracking his safe? That's like stealing. I won't do it!
花子ちゃん どこから
持ってきたの？ その衣装｡
Hanako-chan, where did you get those clothes?
Oh well. I'll do it for my dream!
でも しゃあない｡
夢のためなら ｳﾁは やるで～！
(お妙)花子ちゃん
あまり目立たないようにしてね｡
Hanako-chan, try not to stand out too much.
(花子)あぁっ！
(お妙)花子ちゃん
あなた もう 大阪 帰りなさい｡
Hanako-chan, go back to Osaka already.
(斗夢)まったく 愚かな連中よ｡
Honestly, what fools they all are.
(斗夢)あれしきの奇術も
見抜けぬとは…｡
They can't even figure out such a simple trick...
Are they blind?
(斗夢)ﾔﾂらの目は 節穴か？
Dreams make people blind.
夢は 人を盲目にする｡
おかげで 私は ﾎﾞﾛ儲け｡
Thanks to that, I make quite a killing. I can't quit being a religious leader now.
まったく
教祖様は やめられないねぇ｡
(ｹﾞｯﾌﾟ)
これも ｱﾝﾀの力のおかげだよ｡
This is all thanks to your power.
どうだ？
たまには 一緒に飲まないか？
Why don't you come down from time to time and have a drink with me?
(斗夢)おい そこにいるんだろ？
Hey, you're up there, aren't you?
(新八たち)わぁっ！
ｱｲﾀﾀﾀ…｡
Owowow...
ちょっと… 花子ちゃんが
ｼﾞﾀﾊﾞﾀ暴れるから…｡
Hey. Hanako-chan, you were struggling too much.
(斗夢)なにしてんの？ ｷﾐたち｡
What are you doing?
(新八/お妙)あ…｡
ｱﾀﾀﾀﾀ！
Owowowow.
Oh no. I'm going to go bald!! Bald!
やばい これ ﾊｹﾞる！ 絶対 ﾊｹﾞる!!
ｲｯﾀ～…｡ ご丁寧に
接着剤まで つけてやがらぁ｡
Ah, that hurt. Figures he'd use real glue on it. But how did he do that so fast?
しかし 一瞬で ここまでやるたぁ
いったい どうやって…｡
Gin-chan.
(神楽)銀ちゃん！ やっぱ ｱﾝﾀ
それのほうが ｲｶすぜ！
You really look better like that.
おい ここ 男子便所だぞ｡
Hey, this is the men's bathroom.
So it really was a trick. I thought you had completely fallen for it.
(神楽)やっぱり ｲｶｻﾏだったｱﾙか｡
私 銀ちゃん すっかり
ﾊﾏってしまった思ったｱﾙ｡
You thought I would believe that?
ｵﾚが こんなん信じると思ったか？
どうせ やるなら こんなとこ➡
I was going to destroy this place, so I was checking it out.
つぶしてやろうと思ってな
探り 入れてたんだよ｡
わ… 私もね｡
M-Me, too. I acted like I was tricked, so I could check it out.
探り 入れるために
騙されたふりしたｱﾙ｡
佃煮ごときで そんな…｡
はいはい わかった｡
Tsukudani would never convince me.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
(神楽)ﾎﾝﾄよ！ その証拠に➡
It's true. As proof, I dug up some information on Tomu.
斗夢のこと 調べてきたよ｡
ほぅ？
Oh?
斗夢のﾔﾂは 私たちにやったような
ﾃﾞﾓﾝｽﾄﾚｰｼｮﾝを➡
Tomu's done the same demonstration as he did with us in front of his followers many times.
信者の前で 何度か披露してるね｡
But it's only been pathetic dreams like curing baldness or getting a knock-off Louis Vuitton handbag.
ただ これが
頭のﾊｹﾞ なおしてほしいとか➡
安物のﾊﾞｯｸﾞが欲しいとか
しょぼい夢ばかり｡
He's been granting dreams that are easily attainable.
簡単に実現できる夢ばかり
叶えているｱﾙ｡
He can prepare for anything by asking his believers what their dreams are ahead of time...
事前に 信者から 夢を聞いてりゃ
なんとでもなるわけか…｡
問題は ｵﾚのﾂﾞﾗにせよ
お前のｱﾚにせよ➡
But the problem is how he was able to make my wig and your food appear out of nowhere.
どうやって
一瞬にして 実行したかだな｡
見えねえほど素早いﾔﾂの
仕業とか…｡
Someone so fast they can't be seen... It can't be.
まさかな｡
(神楽)忍者ｱﾙ｡
A ninja.
I saw it on TV.
私 ﾃﾚﾋﾞで観たよ｡
お前 そんなﾍﾞﾀな…｡
That's so cliché...
(服部)ふぅ～｡
(服部)ｲﾃﾃﾃﾃ…｡
Owowowow. Ow. This is bad. Blood came out again.
やべえな また 血 出ちゃったよ｡
(服部)いきみすぎたな ｲﾃﾃ…｡
I clenched too hard. Owowow...
Gin-san, Kagura-chan!!
銀さ～ん 神楽ちゃ～ん！
新八 どうしたね？
Shinpachi, what's wrong?
You need to take a dump? Is it gonna be a photo-finish?
なんだ ｳﾝｺか？
ｳﾝｺもれそうなのか？
大変だ！ 姉上と花子ちゃんが！
Bad news. It's my sister and Hanako-chan!!
♪♪～
Everyone, I have an unfortunate announcement. We had a traitors in our midst.
(斗夢)皆さ～ん
残念なお知らせがあります｡
(斗夢)私たちの仲間から
裏切り者が出ました｡
They snuck into my room and tried to steal your offerings.
彼らは 私の部屋に忍び込み➡
寄付してもらったお布施を
盗み出そうとしました｡
Do you think this is forgivable?!
これを許すことができますか!?
Never!! Die!
(信者)ふざけるな！ 死ね!!
ｲﾀｯ！
皆さん 目を覚ましてください！
Everyone, open your eyes. You're all being tricked by this man...
皆さん この男に… ｲﾃｯ！
You bastard! You threw a rock at me. I'll remember your face!! I'll kill you afterwards!!
ﾃﾒｴ 今 石 投げたな？
顔 覚えとくかんな！
ﾃﾒｴ 絶対 あとで殺すからな!!
(斗夢)私は この者たちに
罰を与えたいと思う｡
I will leave the punishment of these traitors to you!
だが どのような罰を与えるかは
みんなに委ねたい… ｲﾀｯ｡
Dream Catcher holds the power to grant wishes!!
ﾄﾞﾘｰﾑｷｬｯﾁｬｰは 願いを叶える力｡
皆さんで この者たちに
どういった罰を与えたいか➡
Everyone, wish intently for the sort of punishment you want them to receive.
強く念じ… ｲﾀﾞｯ｡
ちょっと 痛いって…｡
Ow! Hey, that hurts!!
さすれば
私たちが手を下さずとも➡
And, these criminals will get the punishment they deserve without us lifting our own hands against them!
この罪人たちに
ふさわしい罰が下る… ｲﾀﾞｯ！
目いった 目…｡
Ow! My eye!!
罰だと!? んなもん
殺しちまえばいいんだ！
Punishment?! Just kill them.
That's right. Kill them!!
(信者たち)そうだ！ 殺せ!!
Kill, kill, kill, kill...
It's decided. You will be punished with death.
決まったな｡ ｷﾐたちは 死刑だ｡
(お妙)やれるものなら
やってみなさい 詐欺師が…｡
Just try it, faker... If you think you can...
夢だ 願いだと
吠えるだけ吠えて 何もしない➡
You just talk about dreams and wishes, but you don't do anything.
まったく めでたい人たちだわ｡
You're all such naïve people.
Otae-chan...
お妙ちゃん…｡
You think you have any power over us?
あなたたちの信じるｲｶｻﾏが
私たちに通ずると思って？
ﾌﾝ この期に及んで➡
You have no proof. Where do you get such confidence at a time like this?
その 根拠のない自信は
どこから来るのだね？
私たちは もっと確かなものを
信じているからよ｡
We believe in something far more powerful than you!
確かなもの？ なんだ それ｡
(どよめき)
What could be more powerful than dreams?
(お妙)それは… 仲間よ！
That would be...
our friends.
なんだ!?
屋根の上に 誰かいるぞ！
What's that?!
There's someone on the roof!
なにっ！ どこだ!?
Wh-What? Where?!
銀ちゃ～ん そこね!!
Gin-chan!! Over there!!
はいっ！
Dream Catcher!
ﾄﾞﾘｰﾑｷｬｯﾁｬｰ！
Unveiled!
見破ったり～!!
(服部)うわっ！
Oh! A ninja!
(花子)あっ 忍者や！
なんだ？ 梁の上から
人が落ちてきたぞ！
What's this? Someone fell from the beams!!
Hey! Hattori-san! Get back up there! What am I paying you for?
ちょっ… 服部さん ｱﾝﾀ 困るよ｡
しっかり隠れててもらわないと！
高い金 払ってるのに｡
I-I can't... S-Something jabbed me in the butt.
(服部)も… もうﾑﾘ…
ｹﾂに おもっくそ 何か刺さった｡
Stop fooling around.
(斗夢)ﾃﾒｴ ふざけんじゃねえぞ！
お庭番衆 ﾘｽﾄﾗされて➡
I picked you up off the streets after the Oniwabanshu downsized you.
[NOTE: The Oniwabanshu was a group of ninjas formed by Yoshimune Tokugawa.]
路頭さまよってるところを
拾ってやったのに｡
Without you, I'm just a man.
(斗夢)ｱﾝﾀがいないと
ｵﾚ ただのおっさんだぞ｡
Sorry. I'm quitting.
(服部)すみません
もう やめますわ｡
The toilets here aren't bidet toilets. My butt can't take it anymore.
ここのﾄｲﾚ ｼｬﾜｰﾄｲﾚじゃないし
もう耐えられませんわ 肛門が｡
Later!!
(服部)じゃあ！
おい～！
Hey!
I-It's a ninja.
(信者)忍者だ！
なんで 斗夢様が忍者を？
Why does Tomu-sama have a ninja?
まだ気づかないんですか？
You still don't get it?
これが ﾄﾞﾘｰﾑｷｬｯﾁｬｰの正体ですよ｡
This is the truth behind the Dream Catcher.
Think back. Did he ever make a dream come true that wasn't simple and concrete things?
思い出して…
この人の叶えてくれた夢って➡
何か具体的な物が欲しいとか
そんなんばっかじゃん｡
この人はねぇ 前もって
あなたたちの夢を ﾁｪｯｸし➡
He pre-interviewed all his converts and chose only dreams that were easy to grant.
叶えられそうな夢だけ ﾁｮｲｽして
あの忍者を 梁の上に忍ばせ➡
He kept a ninja hidden in the beams and acted as if he was performing miracles at swift speeds.
その 目にも止まらぬ速さで
奇跡を演出してただけなんですよ｡
You were tricked.
あなたたちは
騙されていたんです！
Impossible. We would never fall for such a silly trick.
ﾊﾞｶな！
そんな ｱﾎみたいな奇術で➡
ｵﾚたちが
引っ掛かるわけねえだろ！
That's right. I was bald, but now I have a head of hair.
そうじゃ！ ﾜｼなんて ﾊｹﾞてたのに
こんな ﾌｯｻﾌｻに…➡
あ～っ これ ﾂﾞﾗじゃねえか！
(信者)ﾎﾝﾄだ！ なんで 今まで➡
Hey, this is a toupee!
It's true. Why didn't you notice it before?
気づかなかったんだ!?
(信者)いや 抜け毛を➡
Well, I didn't touch it 'cause I didn't want my new hair to fall out!
最小限にしようと
できるだけ 触れんかったから…｡
ﾃﾒｴ 斗夢！ この野郎！
よくも 騙しやがったな!!
Hey, Tomu! You bastard!! How dare you trick us!!
金 返せ ﾃﾒｴ!!
Give us back our money!!
あ…｡
教祖様 何しとんねん｡
Where are you going, Guru?
こんなときこそ
ﾄﾞﾘｰﾑｷｬｯﾁｬｰでしょ？
Why don't you use your Dream Catcher for something like this.
(お妙/花子)助けてくれ って
ﾎｸﾛに願えや!!
Pray to your hairy mole for help!!
ああぁ～っ!!
(花子)ｱｲﾂも ｳﾁらと同じや｡
Like us, he was a pathetic man who was couldn't see anything because he was absorbed in his dream.
夢に溺れて 何も
見えへんようになってしもうた➡
悲しい男や｡
Yes. But the only thing different was you had people to help you.
(お妙)そうね｡ ただ 違うのは➡
溺れたときに
助けてくれる誰かが➡
It's all about whether you have friends or not, isn't it?
いるかどうかってことじゃない？
だから 私が溺れたときは
お願いね 花子ちゃん｡
If I get like that, help me out, okay, Hanako-chan?
Of course. Next time, I'll show you Osaka's kindheartedness.
(花子)当たり前や｡
今度は 大阪の人情 見せたるで｡
D-D-Dream Catcha...
ﾄﾞ ﾄﾞ… ﾄﾞﾘｰﾑｷｬｯﾁｬｰ…｡
どうか ﾎﾞｸを ﾊﾟﾁﾝｺで大勝ちさせ…｡
Please let me win big at pachinko...
なにやってんですか？ 銀さん｡
What are you doing, Gin-san?
[Preview]
Gin-chan, I want to eat a steamed pork bun!
I don't have any. Go ask Santa for one.
You can't fool me.
Even Yuming is singing there's no Santa!
[Yuming = Yumi Matsutoya]
The next episode... Hey, isn't Christmas already over by the next episode?
["People Who Say that Santa Doesn't Really Exist Actually Want to Believe in Him"]
[And the other story is about a battle, Gintoki Sakata versus Zenzo Hattori.]
[Prayer Won't Make Your Worldly Desires Go Away! Control Yourself.]